A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Middle East and Africa Program, Correspondence FA1425
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Middle East and Africa Program, Correspondence
1960-1970
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1425
1.9 Cubic Feet 5 letter document containers
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation's Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program originated in 1958 as the Near East and Africa Program, a regional program area within Overseas Development. The Ford Foundation became more involved in the region with the opening of field offices in Beirut in 1953 and Cairo in 1959. MEA became part of the International Division in 1966 when the Overseas Development Program, along with other international Foundation programs, became part of one International Division. The collection spans from 1960-1970.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence and memoranda from the Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program, including general chronological correspondence files and correspondence from the field offices of Cairo, Lagos, Beirut, Ankara, Nairobi, and Tunis.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series:
1. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970
2. Field Office Correspondence Files, 1960-1968
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2017:087.
Middle East; Africa; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation organization -- Field offices; Correspondence
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970; 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains general circulating correspondence and memoranda files from the Middle East and Africa Program. The correspondence relates to potential grant projects, field office finances, personnel, and general office issues. Individuals who received and responded to the correspondence and memoranda include: J. Wayne Fredericks, Wilbert LeMelle, Thomas Scott, Willard Hertz, Ben Lewis, William T. Irelan, William A. Herman, Haskell G. Ward, Ann W. Noyes, Betty White, David Bell, Francis Sutton, Howard Swearer, William P. Gormbley, Mr. Horah, Courtney Nelson, Elisa Scatena, John A. Quinn, David Pfanner, Elsie Capozzi, Oscar Harkavy, James Himes, George Zeidenstein, Mr. Bunnell, Mr. Miller, and Miss Klimbach.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 April 2-10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Robert E. Hunter, Darryl Forde, G. J. Leibbrandt, Dr. Wilton Dillon, Frederick S. Arkhurst, Joesph Applegate, James A. Moss, Deborah Schatz, Gary R. Epler, Kacem Ben-Hamza, Makram A. Tadros, H. M. Tartir, Lowell Hardin, Willard J. Hertz, A. H. Hanson, Nils Karlgard, Jan Koopman, Herman De Haas, Lloyd H. Belz, Ernest Cole, Aaron Segel, Ivor Nelson, Charles Hightower, Vernon McKay, Leo Cefkind, Gerry Bender, John Shingler, Patrick Omera, Mike Samuels, Sylvester Whitaker, John J. Conyers, Jr., Charles C. Diggs, Jr., Leonard Thompson, Leo Kuper, James Brewer, Martin Legassick, Richard Stevens, John Marcum, George Shepherd, Dennis Brutus, Ron Shevelew, Kenneth Grundy, Jeffrey A. Gray, Joseph Fisher, Edward S. Ellenberg, Boyce M. Bennett, Jean E. Lowrie, Ali Mohammad Awartani, Warren M. Fraser, Yari Ben-Dov, Lewis M. Mukattash, H. Cheikhrouhou, James T. Ivy, Edgar Edwards, G. K. Helleiner, Heinz A. Abersfeller, Richard A. Fehnel, Elizabeth Demarest, Nancy Owings, David R. Smock, Brian M. du Toit, Blanchard Hiatt, Therese E. Nadeau, John G. McNeely, Jacqueline Desoer, W. L. Swett, Jr., Sue Liggett, and David A. Anderson
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 April 15-24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Leo Alting von Geusau, Edwin Young, Robert W. Erickson, Guy Arnold, Val Gray Ward, Freida High, Henry Franklin Jackson, Sylvia V. Kinney, Ukanga C. Mudakha, Joel O. Nwagbaraocha, Josephine Taylor, Barbara Payne, Lois L. Woods, Martin A. Alugbuo, Mattye Laverne Brandon, Eloise Morris Canzater, Theodore R. Canzater, Rachelle E. Carraway, Genen Clarke, John Clarke, Ida V. Clark, Fred Gandy, Jr., Randall Robinson, Mariea Rayford, Norma Gyebi, Rex C. Fortune, Jr., David F. Dorsey, Rose Mary Sanders, Henry Sanders, Roslyn Baltimore, Ida Faye Rousseau, Thelma H. Rucker, Charles E. Simmons III, Constance B. Hilliard, Herbert Anderson, Herman D. Blackman, Patricia M. Downs, J. Michael Turner, Gloria C. Lindsey, Rafat Ibrahimoglu, Charles Longbottom, Claire Nader, Franklin H. Williams, Edgar Edwards, Knud Erik Svendsen, Clifford H. Prator, R. D. Osler, Raymund F. Wood, Peider Konz, J. E. Kariuki, Richard B. Myer, Paul O. Proehl, Mark W. Cannon, A. H. Rubenstein, Frank J. Moore, Chancellor Williams, John I. Akpan, Raymond B. Buker, Winifred Armstrong, Patricia Mackay, Josephine Mitchell, Michael Sinclair, Allen LeBel, William A. Polk, Peter Benedict, Walter Leonard, Jeffrey Butler, Irving K. Fox, Joseph Llorens, R. Thomas Garrett, Jesse Dan Russell, Roy Thompson, E. Drostby, Thomas E. Benner, Terrance S. Bannister, Sue Liggett, Thomas R. Carvlin, Ronald Katana, Myer Cohen, E. A. Schroeder, Sheleme Sendaba, Joseph Mutyaga, Eduard Nsimbi, Josephat Kasaiji, Dominic Milazi, Salma Tejpar, Abdulsemed Abdurhman, Saba Abraha, Dean Barnes, G. K. Helleiner, Ragaei El Mallakh, Wolfgang Stolper, Milton O. Pella, Kwaowo Adubofour, William A. Brown, Denis Griddal, Doris Yeboah, Gabriel A. Atowo, Kesington Olujimi Odukoya, Francis O'Bai Kabia, Lamin-A-N-Bojang, Jospeh Lyonga, Beatrice Amaning, Joseph Kwan Lamptey, Abraham M. Eseme, K. Osei-Ntem, Romanns C. Nwachukwu, Charles Hightower, Edwin M. Martin, Leonard Thompson, Vernon McKay, C. Eric Lincoln, Vincent Harding, Lensana S. Hindolo, Nwojo K. Ugah, Ferdinand Mangria, Michael U. Ikpe, B. I. Nwafor, Bonaventure A. Achinanya, Dasmond Aboagye, S. E. Saidu, Simon Mokake, Richard Myer, Burt Swanson, James T. Ivy, Robert C. Anderson, Leon Weiner
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 April 24-May 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: John P. Robin, Jacob A. A. Atanga, Reverend Joseph S. Nunziato, Daryll Forde, Walter J. Leonard, Robert D. Loken, T. R. Ilunga-Tshibamba, James Duffy, F. Sule Atikkan, James R. Curley, Kieran M. Bracken, Edmund Stefurak, Najeeb Khadouri, Roderick Davison, Herbert Albrecht, O. D. Koht Norbye, George Clark, El Mallakh, Mel Driumer, Jerome Domatob, Folavin Solavin, Charles O. Todman, Jr., Daniel Veinfeld, Nancy Owings, Sue Liggett, Thelma H. Rucker, Alexandra Simon, J. E. Kariuki, Emile Sady, Susan Gitelson, Joseph P. Wilkins, David F. Dorsey, Rose Mary Sanders, Mariea L. Rayford, Kieran M. Bracken, Gwendolen M. Carter, Clifford C. Coles, Thelma H. Rucker, Leo Alting von Geusau, Hugh Tracey, Wubishet Dilnessahu, Robert Hind, Raymond F/ Hopkins, J. E. Kariuki, David Heaps, Namzy Azer Ibrahim, Peter T. Nulty, Richard C. Slama, Michael Kelly, Albert H. Rubenstein, Sue Liggett, and Thomas Cutler
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 May 7-15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Darragh Park, Moustafa Mohamed Raafat, Israel M. Horowitz, Barbara R. Spannaus, Chandler Morse, Douglas Keare, George M. Platt, William de Spoelberch, William J. Burke, Orin D. Parker, John Blackmore, Edward L. Webb, Salua Nour, Richard B. Myer, Hyman R. Shevelew, Gerald J. Bender, John Marcum, Kenneth W. Grundy, J. Leo Cefkin, Jeffrey Butler, Vivian Henderson, Lewis A. Gist, Vincent Harding, Thomas E. Lucas, Ibok Esema, Mohamoud Saleh, Adrian K. Irving, Ian A. Hodson, Mary Rita Conlon, Anne de Lattre, J. E. Kariuki, J. Tweneba-Kodua, E. A. Winful, Frank W. Kolmin, and Gwendolen M. Carter
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 May 19-22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Barbara Payne, George Olu Abalu, Omire Nobi, Moses Conteh, Desmond B. Johnson, S. B. Baryeh, Erico Tamajong, William Dawson, J. M. P. Sonnie, Oluwole Olakojo, T. Owolabi, M. A. Adeyanju, Greta Avery, Emmanuel Sarpong Akowush, Sam Carter, Philippe Pindi, Gerard Ciparisse, Dan B. Jacobs, Emmanuel Osuaguse, Bernard Houle, Gabriel Lawrence, J. O. Simaren, Denise C. Dabney, Cosmos Ouekpa, Alfred A. Adewuyi, Emmanuel Quarpong, Mosunmola Omibiyi, Duro Oyekanle, D. Wonnie, William Gardner, Loulou Lewis, Isaac T. Gblee, Yinka Sholaja, Roslyn Baltimore, Otto M. Lifongo, Timothy Gbile Adewale, Regina Hughes, Peter Peter, Frank J. Moore, Gregory V. Delin, Orin Parker, Nuri Shafiq, Sharifa M. Zawawi, Clifford Prator, S. B. Ogembo, F. W. Muraya, Michael Stern, Dale L. Soderberg, Frank Barton, Michael P. Fogarty, C. Worth Howard, Nazmy Azer Ibrahim, M. Inagaki, Ali Hassan Gulaid, Csaba Cauros, Sechdev Singh Seyan, Abdulsemed Abdurhman, Michael A. Samuels, Andre Laplante, Lez Edmond, Sue Liggett, J. O. Udoji, and Jack Larned
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 May 25-28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: William T. Coleman, Jr., Charles Longbottom, Cyrus R. Vance, Jeffrey Butler, Edward H. Levi, P. M. Githinji, George A. Wing, Edward Mosk, Rose Mary Sanders, Rex C. Fortune, Jr., Norma Gyebi, Mariea L. Rayford, David F. Dorsey, Jr., Randall M. Robinson, Henry Sanders, George Chambers, G. Edward Clark, Nassar Farhan, Robert C. Repetto, Conrad Stucky, A. H. Hanson, M. Moncef Nafti, Godwin-Collins Onyeledo, Georgia Elrod, and P. E. L. Fellowes
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 June 1-5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Lord Fulton of Falmer, Francis O. Wilcox, Robert E. Hunter, Philip M. Allen, Darrel Smith, Robert W. Erickson, Ali Awartani, Hugh Tracey, Dwight Brothers, Herbert Albrecht, Peter A. Diaconoff, Eleanor McKinney, Anne E. Hope, S. A. Solade Adams, Sue Liggett, Hollister Kent, Clifford H. Prator, King Carr, and A. L. Adu
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 June 9-19 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Najeeb Halaby, Cyrus Vance, C. Packard Wolle, Leland Barrows, Raoul Grenier, Robert F. Goheen, Sean MacBride, William J. Chambliss, Donald H. McKnight, Donald R. Morris, P. Chike Onwuachi, Vincent Harding, W. D. Hoeye, Armistead P. Rood, Jerry B. Eckert, Paul Heath, Paul Engle, James H. Robinson, Israel M. Horowitz, Ephraim Young, Abdel-Rahman El-Hamlawi, Daniel M. Shimabuku, Ahmed Fathy Bahig, G.S. Hatton, Joseph E. Johnson, P. E. L Fellowes, Ralph A. Bradley, Muhsin S. Mahdi, Chahira Hopper, S. T. M. Sukati, Marvin E. Rozen, Herbert Albrecht, Hugh P. Bradley, Alemayehu Tefera, Abdullahi Mohamoud Hassan, Celestin Walusimbi-Musoke, Fred Ruefer, Leslie E. Grayson, A. H. Hanson, Douglas Keare, Peter B. Clark, Idris R. Traylor, Nicholas D. Ofiaja, C. Scott Kelly, Doutor Carlos Castro Carvalho, William A. Herman, Sister Gertrude, E. A. Toye, Sister M. Hilda McDermott, Abbey R. Maine, George N. Lindsey, Richard Brand, J. O. Obateru, Ann Cook, Guy Arnold, William C. Walzer, Michael Idowu Ayeni, Emanuel C. Otchere-Agyei, Paul O. Okonkwo, Emmanuel Sarpong Akowuah, Lamin Kamara, Allen A. Hyman, R. Freeman Butts, Drid Williams, Candy Herring, R. D. Osler, Sue Liggett, Mary Rita Conlon, Valentine S. Muskanya, John B. Seal, D. N. Ndegwa, James C. N. Paul, Arthur T. Porter, Robert Chambers, R. D. Osler
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 June 19-26 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Kenneth Glynn, Aklilu Habte, Dwight Brothers, Calo A. Alain, Shewarega Kidane, Michael Fogarty, Gregory Rigsby, Albert H. Rubenstein, Nana Mehomo, Robert B. Myer, Darragh Park, Harold C. Bradley, Aaron Segal, Bernard Berelson, Ivo Crnic, Natasha Deakin, and Nicole Lemerche
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 June 25-July 3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: David Anderson, John Henrik Clarke, Jo-Anne Brown, O. Edoh, P. S. S. Kawa, Felex Nwosu, Secondhand Clothing Trading Company, Keith D. Nunes, William M. Evan, E. D. Bergmann, Harihar M. Patel, Nicholas G. G. Makura, John P. Robin, Diwght S. Brothers, O. J. Vesey Holt, Albert A. Mavrinac, Marilyn Raschka, Harold Moss, Milton A. Feinberg, John Mwai Murani, E. C. Chirwa, Benjamin H. Read, E. E. Mensah, Raymond H. Tremblay, Johan D. van der Vyver, A. Opare Addo, Ato Aberra Moltat, Herbert Priestley, Robert S. Browne, R. S. Pritchard, K. A. Familoni, Geoffrey C. A. Ekechukwu, Festus Abayomi Orekoya, E. K. Duodu, Samuel Somuah, J. Adekanmi Adediran, Bartholomew E. Okoduwa, Nsima J. Akpadiah, Kenneth D. Carlander, K. B. Sannoh, Gregory Archibong, Maxime-Leopold Zollner, Dan Curtis, Ribhi El-Hasan, Ivo Crnic, Chanoch Rinott, Randall M. Robinson, Nancy Owings, Norma Gyebi, David F. Dorsey, Rex C. Fortune, and Mariea L. Rayford
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 July 6-10 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: S. Biobaku, H. M. R. Keyes, Kamal Ali Beyoghlow, William H. Dorsey, S. Paul Azard, Dan Bavly, Cecil Hourani, H. Ben-Shahar, Lorraine Dadgar, Jamshid Naghizadeh, Richard Klein, Richard B. Myer, Robert W. Gregg, Richard Peters, Hassan Gabr, Charles Runyon, Mont H. Saunderson, Mesmako Asrat, C. J. Zvobgo, Emmanuel E. Ekama, M. I. Ayeni, Martin L. Gross, Kanayo Onyilogwu, Ebenezer Tackie, Joncker R. Biandudi, Jr., Joe Alade, Gladys C. Warden, Theodore D. Olomole, Joseph Mensah, Seymour W. James, William A. Glaser Patricia K. Tsien, Benjamin Christian Okai, Raymond A. Adjebeng, William E. Dadson, E. Napoleon, Sebastian E. L. Fomanka, Lloyd N. Ferguson, Ambassador Davidson Nicol, Hyman R. Shevelew, Charles C. Nwokedi, George W. Shepherd, Jr., Maurice Jackson, Kenneth H. Niedfeldt, Mohamed Khadar, Loel K. Acker, Mr. and Mrs. Henry Sanders, and Geraldine Amos
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 July 10-17 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: James Duffy, E. Jefferson Murphy, James W. Kiriazis, A. H. Hakimi, Yuksel Gozen, Sydney W. Head, Wesley S. Edwards, Leon Brown, Robert N. Hornick, Richard Peters, Wayne McGown, William Young, Emmanuel G. Kasonde, Steven Jones, Mohamed Khadar, J. O. Osuntokun, Adedotun Layade, Kingsley Amporo, Juya Vanda, Luke Okoli, Robert Bedford, T. N. Senesie, Humphrey A. Ugvesia, Paul J. Mawo, John R. E. K. Anati, August P. Hackbart, Mary Rita Conlon, and Stanley I. Hallett
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 July 21-24 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: Robert H. Maybury, Wendy Peters, Nancy Owings, Pierre Fougeyrollas, Richard B. Myer, David Robinson Munisi, Edmund Jones Okoe Mensah, Andre Raynauld, David Barzilai, David K. Munro, Ivo Crnic, Ahmad Wali Naibi, Ahmed Sarhan, Vern Preheim, George Ishaggi, Thomas H. Mudambui, Jeffrey S. Gruber, M. D. Adeyemo, Girmachew Azbite, Arthur L. Levi, J. D. Van der Vyver, Dorothy Warns, Michael Nwaokocha, Chester J. Antieau, Richard D. Edwards, Joseph A. Mills Odai, Opare Addo, Patrick O. Erhabor, Susan A. Halliday, Edward Stone, E. F. Margai, Jacob N. Nda, Gerald L. Davis, John Pumjifadiora, Napoleon Aburine, T. E. Mbuagbaw, Julius Adewumi, A. O. Ogunkola, Nathan S. O. Obuh, Otto M. Lifongo, F. M. K. Eghan, Kehinde Adeloye, and Mary Rita Conlon
  - Circulating Chron, 1970 July 24-31 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Inter-office memoranda and correspondence with: R. Freeman Butts, H. M. B. Somade, Marvin Levich, D. W. Lockard, Ignacio Narvaez, Lee B. Harris, Bernard Marsden, Charlotte Jacobson, Charles J. Adams, A. R. Shaheen, Anwar Guirguis Ibrahim, El-Salim Sulieman, Joe W. Neal, Sue Liggett, Belaynesh Tekester, Arthur L. Levi, Leonard A. De Vos, Emory J. West, Alex Obiero-Onyango, Cyril Ritchie, Channing B. Richardson, Anne Sandry, Horace J. Landry, Elwyn M. Williams, John J. Jameison, Jr., Gabriel E. Okon, Albert H. Rubenstein, Phyllis Hacin, Michael N. Ankrah, Bernard O. Mgbenka, S. K. Naik, Dennis Okoth, Michael Kelly, and Loel K. Acker
- Field Office Correspondence Files, 1960-1968; 2
  Individual folders are arranged reverse chronologically
  Contains correspondence files from the field offices within the Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program, including Cairo, Lagos, Beirut, Ankara, Nairobi, Tunis
  - Cairo Office, No. 1, 1960 May-1967 May (Box 2, Folder 15, Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    Folder 15: 1967 January-1967 May
    Folder 16: 1966 June-December
    Folder 17: 1960 May-1966 May
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, US Embassy demands, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Cairo Office from 1962-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, Donald M. Stewart, James S. Lipscomb, Nabil Haddad, and Harvey Hall
  - Cairo Office, No. 2, 1967 June-1968 April (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    Folder 18: 1967 September-1968 April
    Folder 19: 1967 June-August
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, US Embassy demands, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Cairo Office from 1962-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, Donald M. Stewart, James S. Lipscomb, Nabil Haddad, and Harvey Hall. Folder 19 contains telegrams and memoranda regarding Ford Foundation staff and families leaving Cairo due to increasing unrest in the Middle East in May 1967.
  - Lagos Office, No. 1, 1964 August-1966 November (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    Folder 20: 1966 August-November
    Folder 21: 1966 January-July
    Folder 22: 1964 August-1965 December
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Lagos Office from 1964-1966. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, David Heaps, Frank J. Moore, and James T. Ivy
  - Lagos Office, No. 2, 1967 January-December (Box 3, Folder 23, Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    Folder 23: 1967 July-December
    Folder 24: 1967 April-June
    Folder 25: 1967 January-March
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Lagos Office from 1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, David Heaps, Frank J. Moore, and James T. Ivy
  - Lagos Office, No. 3, 1968 January-March (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Lagos Office from 1968. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, David Heaps, Frank J. Moore, and James T. Ivy
  - Beirut Office, 1967 April-1964 April (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
    Folder 27: 1967 April-July
    Folder 28: 1966 August-1967 June
    Folder 29: 1964 April-1966 August
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Beirut Office from 1964-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) W. Hugh Walker, J. Donald Kingsley, Harvey P. Hall, James T. Ivy, Clark Bloom, and David Heaps
  - Ankara Office No. 1, 1963 December-1967 November (Box 4, Folder 30-32)
    Folder 30: 1966 December-1967 November
    Folder 31: 1965 October-1966 November
    Folder 32: 1963 December-1965 September
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Ankara Office from 1964-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, James T. Ivy, Robert Kerwin, and Eugene Northrop
  - Ankara Office No. 2, 1968 January-March (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Ankara Office from 1968. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley and Eugene Northrop.
  - Nairobi Office, 1963 September-1968 March (Box 5, Folder 34-36)
    Folder 34: 1967 August-1968 March
    Folder 35: 1967 February-July
    Folder 36: 1963 September-1967 January
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Nairobi Office from 1963-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, John Robin, James T. Ivy, and David R. Smock
  - Tunis Office, 1964 September-1967 June (Box 5, Folder 37-39)
    Folder 37: 1967 June-December
    Folder 38: 1966 September-1967 December
    Folder 39: 1964 September-1966 August
    Contains memoranda, telegrams, and correspondence regarding finances, personnel, and everyday office life of the Ford Foundation's Tunis Office from 1964-1967. Most memoranda are from (or involve) J. Donald Kingsley, David Heaps, Donald Stewart, and James Hardy.